Raluca-Maria Sandu

I am currently finishing my PhD Degree in Biomedical Engineering, previously having graduated with an MSc in the same field and a BSc in Control Engineering and Applied Informatics. My research interests are machine learning, computer vision, statistics, and robotics.



EDUCATION

University of Bern, ARTORG Center for Biomedical Engineering *PhD in Biomedical Engineering** MAY 2017 – JAN 2021

My project was part of a European Innovative Training Network (HiperNav) funded through a Marie Skłodowska-Curie grant.

Thesis: "Quantitative assessment of ablation treatments for liver tumours – image-based efficacy analysis and predictive modelling".

RWTH Aachen University, Faculty of Medicine

MSc in Biomedical Engineering

OCT 2014 - MAR 2017

Thesis: "Image Segmentation and Semantic Description: Tools and

Analytics" conducted at Philips Research Eindhoven, NL

Thesis Project Grade: 100%

GPA: 83%

POLITEHNICA University of Bucharest

BSc in Control Engineering and Applied Informatics OCT 2010 – JUL 2014

Thesis: "Volumetric Capnography Respiratory Signals for Spontaneously Breathing Subjects" conducted at Philips Research Eindhoven, NL

Thesis Project Grade: 98%

GPA: 83% (Ranked 46 out 202 graduates)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Philips Research Eindhoven, Personal Care and Wellness Department

Research & Development Graduate Student JUL 2016 – MAR 2017 (9 months) Designed and developed a web-based application for 2D image annotation. Built image processing and machine learning algorithms for classification of anatomical skin surface structures (semantic segmentation).

Philips Research Eindhoven, Personal Care and Wellness Department *Research & Development Intern* APR 2016 – JUN 2016 (3 months)

Applied image processing to extract physiological features that measure the effect of a specific diet on skin.

Joint Research Centre for Computational Biomedicine, RWTH Aachen

Student Research Assistant (HiWi) NOV 2014 – JUL 2015 (9 months)

Analysed interactions between cancer cell lines.

Philips Research Eindhoven, Personal Health Department

Research & Development Intern JUL 2013 – OCT 2013 (4 months)

Used signal processing methods for respiratory signals feature extraction.

Philips Research Eindhoven, Personal Health Department

Research & Development Intern JUL 2012 – SEP 2012 (9 months)

Implemented data mining techniques for chronic heart failure patients.

CONTACT

E-mail: raluca-sandu@rwth-aachen.de

Website: raluca-san.github.io GitHub: github.com/raluca-san

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rmsandu

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ Data Science
- ✓ Machine Learning
- ✓ Signal & Image Processing
- ✓ Statistical Analysis
- ✓ Python (scikit-learn, numpy)
- ✓ RStudio
- ✓ MATLAB
- ✓ Git (GitHub, Bitbucket)
- ✓ Bash, Linux
- ✓ HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
- ✓ SQL
- ✓ C/C++/C#

OTHER SKILLS

- ✓ Graphic Design (InkScape, Gimp)
- ✓ Presentation Design
- ✓ Scientific Writing

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent (C1)

German: Intermediate (B2)

French: Intermediate (B1)

RESEARCH OUTPUT

Peer-Reviewed Journal Publications

- ✓ Frontiers in Oncology, Cancer Imaging and Image-directed Interventions, OCT 2020 (accepted) "Volumetric Quantitative Ablation Margins for Assessment of Ablation Completeness in Thermal Ablation of Liver Tumours" (R.M. Sandu, I. Paolucci, R. Sznitman, S. Weber, P. Tinguely)
- ✓ IEEE Open Journal of Engineering in Medicine and Biology, FEB 2020 "Ultrasound based planning and navigation for non-anatomical liver resections an ex-vivo study." (I. Paolucci, **R.M. Sandu**, L. Sahli, G.A. Prevost, D. Candinas, A. Lachenmayer)

Book Chapter

✓ Liver Pathology, Intechopen, OCT 2019
"Stereotactic Image-Guidance for Ablation of Malignant Liver Tumors." (I. Paolucci, R.M. Sandu, P. Tinguely, S. Weber, A. Lachenmayer)

Conference Publications

- ✓ IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBS) International Student Conference, NOV 2019, Magdeburg (Germany)
 - "Quantitative Volumetric Assessment of CT-guided Ablation Treatments for Colorectal Liver" (**R.M.** Sandu, I. Paolucci, J. Freedman, P. Tinguely, S. Weber)
- ✓ 31st Conference of the international Society for Medical Innovation and Technology (iSMIT), OCT 2019, Heilbronn (Germany)
 - "Quantitative Volumetric Assessment of Percutaneous Ablation Treatments for Colorectal Liver Metastases." (R.M. Sandu, I. Paolucci, J. Freedman, P. Tinguely, S. Weber)
- ✓ CURAC 18th Annual Meeting of the German Society for Computer- and Robot-Assisted Surgery, SEP 2019, Reutligen (Germany)
 - "Quantitative volumetric assessment of percutaneous image-guided microwave ablations for colorectal liver metastases" (R.M. Sandu, I. Paolucci, J. Freedman, P. Tinguely, S. Weber)
- ✓ CURAC 17th Annual Meeting of the German Society for Computer- and Robot-Assisted Surgery SEP 2018, Leipzig (Germany)
 - "A Framework for The Quantitative Assessment of Image-guided Percutaneous Ablation of Hepatic Lesions" (R. Hrabuska, **R.M. Sandu,** I. Paolucci, S. Weber)

Public Speaking/Conference Talks

- ✓ Maurice E. Müller Memorial Event at Inselspital Bern, MAR 2018 "Minimally Invasive Treatment of Liver Tumours" (Invited Speaker)
- ✓ ECALSS Congress (European Computer Assisted Liver Surgery Society) OCT 2019 "Quantitative ablation Methodology and Results from the MAVERRIC Study" (Conference Talk)

CERTIFICATES

- ✓ Good Clinical Practice (GCP) Certificate, CTU Bern Clinical Investigators I: Basic GCP & clinical research training Course, FEB 2019
- ✓ Zertifikat Niveau B1, Sprachenzentrum der RWTH Aachen, SEP 2015, score 95% German Language classes undertaken at the University of Bern (2017-2019) B2.2 level.
- ✓ Erasmus Mobility Placement Grant for Internship at Philips Research Netherlands, JUN 2012
- ✓ Artificial Intelligence Course in partnership with Stanford School of Engineering, DEC 2011 Completed in the top 25% of the class with a score of 95.1%.
- ✓ Certificate in Advanced English CAE, University of Cambridge ESOL, JUN 2009, grade A
- ✓ Diplôme d'études en langue française DELF B1, FEB 2009, score 80%

HOBBIES

- ✓ Volunteering
 Vice-President Local Committee IAESTE Bern, Switzerland, https://www.iaeste.ch/en/
- ✓ Hiking, Skiing, Snowboarding, Surfing